在这里，我们有两个链接机器人，就像我们刚看到的那样，但这一次我们要去
Here we have the same two link robot as we just looked at but this time we're going to
使用分析方法解决它，即我们将更多地依赖于代数，
solve it using an analytical approach, that is we're going to rely much more on algebra,
特殊的线性代数而不是几何。我们有一个表达式E，它是同质的
particular linear algebra rather than geometry. We have an expression E, which is the homogeneous
代表机器人事件的姿势的变换，我们看了这个
transformation which represents the pose of the robots endefector and we looked at this
在上一个讲座中，我们可以将先行者姿势写成一个基本同质的序列
in the last lecture, we can write the endefector pose as a sequence of elementary homogeneous
转换。通过Q1旋转，沿X方向平移A1，旋转
transformations. A rotation by Q1, a translation along the X direction by A1, a rotation by
Q2然后通过A2在X方向上进行平移。如果我将其展开，则将所有数据相乘
Q2 and then a translation in the X direction by A2. If I expand this out, multiply all
转换在一起，我得到这里显示的表达;一个三乘三的同质变换
the transformations together, I get the expression shown here; a three by three homogeneous transformation
矩阵表示机器人的行为者的姿势。
matrix representing the pose of the robot's endefector.
现在对于这个特殊的双链机器人，我们只关心它的位置
Now for this particular two link robot, we are only interested in the position of its
exefector，它是X和Y坐标，它们是同质中的这两个元素
endefector, it's X and Y co-ordinate and they are these two elements within the homogeneous
转换矩阵，所以我要复制出来。所以这又是我们的表达
transformation matrix, so I'm going to copy those out. So here again is our expression
对于X和Y以及我们要做的是一个相当普遍的技巧，我们将会解决问题
for X and Y and what we're going to do is a fairly common trick, we're going to square
并添加这两个方程式，我得到一个看起来像这样的关系。现在我可以解决了
and add these two equations and I get a relationship that looks like this. Now I can solve for
根据完成者姿势X和Y以及机器人常数A1和A2的关节角度Q2。
the joint angle Q2 in terms of the endefector pose X and Y and the robot's constants A1 and A2.
现在我要做的是应用角度身份的总和。我要扩展它们
Now what I'm going to do is apply the sum of angles identity. I'm going to expand these
条件，Q1加Q2的正弦或Q1加Q2的cos，以使生活更轻松一点，我
terms, sine of Q1 plus Q2 or cos of Q1 plus Q2 and to make life a little bit easier, I'm
要做一些变电站，所以无论我在哪里有cosQ2，我都要写C2和哪里
going to make some substations, so where ever I had cos Q2, I'm going to write C2 and where
我有没有正常的Q2，我要写S2。当人们这是一个相当普遍的速记
ever I had sine Q2, I’m going to write S2. It's a fairly common shorthand when people
正在研究机器人运动方程。以下是制作这些方程式后的方程式
are looking at robot kinematic equations. And here are the equations after making those
换人。看看这两个方程式，我可以看出它们很好地融入了它们
substitutions. Looking at these two equations, I can see that they fall into a very well
已知的形式，对于那种形式，有一个众所周知的解决方案。所以我要考虑一下
known form and for that form there is a very well known solution. So I'm going to consider
只是其中一个方程，Y的等式，并使用我们众所周知的身份和它
just one of the equations, the equation for Y and using our well known identity and it's
解决方案，我可以确定变量的值小a，小b和小c
solution, I can determine the values for the variables little a, little b and little c
一旦我确定了那些，那么我可以写下Q1的解决方案
and once I've determined those, then I can just write down the solution for Q1, which
在这种特殊情况下，它相当于theta。
is the equivalent of theta in this particular case.
这里再次是我们对Q1的表达，复制了上一张幻灯片，我们可能还记得
Here again is our expression for Q1, copied over from the previous slide and we may remember
从我们工作的早期开始，我们确定了这种特殊的关系;X平方加
from earlier in our workings that we determined this particular relationship; X squared plus
Y平方等于这个特殊的复杂表达式。所以我可以用和替代
Y squared is equal to this particular complex expression. So I can substitute that in and
做一些简化，我最终得到Q1的这种稍微不那么复杂的表达式。和
do some simplification and I end up with this slightly less complex expression for Q1. And
它与我在上一节中按照几何方法得到的表达式相同。
it is the same expression that I got following the geometric approach in the previous section.